A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 13949-17726 FA739F
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Counseling in today's real world: leading through diversity to achieve excellence, copyright (Reports 015234), 1997 (Box 767, Reel R-9306)
  Multiculturalism -- Education; Multiculturalism -- Education, Elementary; School improvement programs -- United States; Educational equalization -- United States; Elementary schools -- United States
- Guidelines for serving immigrant - language minority students with special needs: An NCAS booklet for immigrant parents, communities, and schools (Reports 015235), 1991 (Box 767, Reel R-9306)
  Emigration and immigration -- Education -- United States; Special education -- United States; Student assistance programs -- United States; Educational equalization -- United States; School improvement programs -- United States; Emigration and immigration
- New groups and new challenges in the midst of national anti-immigrant hysteria: an assessment report (Reports 015236), 1993 (Box 767, Reel R-9306)
  "In an increasingly anti-immigrant society... immigrant students face the challenges of ethnocentrism, language restrictionism, anti-immigrant legislation, dwindling resources, anti-immigrant violence, and racism. Immigrant students have become the scapeg
  Immigrants -- Students -- United States; Racism -- United States; Educators -- Interviews
- Conventional arms control after the Cold War: the political and strategic relevance of the Treaty on Conventional Armed Forces in Europe (Reports 015237), 1993 (Box 767, Reel R-9306)
  Doctoral thesis submitted July 1993 for doctor of Philosophy, Department of War Studies, King's College London.[…]"This study offers a detailed analysis of the political origins the CFE Treaty, as well as an assessment of its strategic relevance in post-Cold War Europe. It focuses on how external political events, such as German unification and the disintegration of
  09001128
  King's College London
  Cold War; Arms control -- Europe
- The UMC guide to documentation: Program report 91-2 (Reports 015238), 1991 (Box 768, Reel R-9306)
  "The Urban Mathematics Collaborative (UMC) Documentation Project, under the direction of Professor Thomas Romberg at the University of Wisconsin-Madison, fulfilled an important role in the UMC project through collecting, managing, and interpreting data to
  Education and Culture; Urban Poverty program
  08500224
  The Regents of the University of Wisconsin
  The Urban Mathematics Collaborative guide to documentation: program report 91-2
  Mathematics -- Study and teaching -- United States -- Documentation; Mathematics -- Documentation; Education -- Mathematics -- Documentation
- Reports and recommendations on program related investments (Reports 015239), 1991 (Box 768, Reel R-9306)
  Endowments -- Program-related investments; Nonprofit organizations -- Finance
- Cashing in: a nonprofit's introduction to borrowing money (Reports 015240), 1990 (Box 768, Reel R-9306)
  Rights and Social Justice;Governance and Public Policy
  08900976
  Puerto Rico Community Foundation, Inc.
  Nonprofit organizations -- Finance; Loans
- Health and human rights in Burma (Myanmar) (Reports 015241), 1991 (Box 768, Reel R-9306)
  News from Physicians for Human Rights
  Human rights -- Health aspects -- Burma; Medical care -- Burma; Human rights -- Burma
- Characteristics and attitudes of frequent participants in the Urban Mathematics Collaboratives: Results of the secondary mathematics teacher questionnaire (Reports 015242), 1989 (Box 768, Reel R-9306)
  Mathematics -- Study and teaching; Mathematics teachers -- Attitudes; Educators -- Mathematics -- Attitudes; Mathematics -- Study and teaching -- Research; Mathematics teachers -- Research; Educators -- Mathematics -- Research
- Mathematics teachers' views about teaching as a profession: Final results of a four year longitudinal study (Reports 015243), 1991 (Box 768, Reel R-9306)
- Teachers' conceptions of mathematics and mathematics education (Reports 015244), 1990 (Box 768, Reel R-9306)
  Mathematics teachers -- Attitudes -- Research; Mathematics -- Study and teaching -- Research
- Preliminary studies of social forestry in Bangladesh (Reports 015245), 1991 (Box 768, Reel R-9306)
  Asia/Bangladesh;Asia/India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  08500421
  Forests and forestry -- Bangladesh -- Social aspects
- Challenging our assumptions: new strategies for serving Hispanics (Reports 015246), 1995 (Box 768, Reel R-9306)
  "Convening two major dialogue meanings - one in Philadelphia and the other in Washington, D.C.... for recognizing Big Brothers / Big sisters of America's need to address the issue of why so few Hispanic men and women are volunteer mentors in their lives."
  09651345
  Big Brothers/Big Sisters of America
  Mentoring -- Hispanic Americans; Voluntarism -- Hispanic Americans; Social work with youth -- Hispanic American women; Hispanic American men
- Background report: Connecticut Supportive Housing Demonstration Program (Reports 015247), 1994 (Box 768, Reel R-9306)
  09300443
  Corporation for Supportive Housing
  Homeless persons -- Housing -- Connecticut -- Finance; Homeless persons -- Services for -- Connecticut; Homeless persons -- Services for -- Finance -- Connecticut; Housing -- Finance -- Connecticut
- Evaluation of the Park Homeless Outreach Project (Reports 015248), 1995 (Box 768, Reel R-9306)
  Homeless persons -- Services for -- New York; Homeless persons -- Services for -- Evaluation -- New York
- Not just building housing, building a future: Corporation for Supportive Housing: annual report (Reports 015249), 1995 (Box 768, Reel R-9306)
  Housing -- United States; Homeless persons -- Housing -- United States; Housing -- Endowments; Housing -- Finance; Nonprofit organizations
- Supportive housing: New York State's solution to homelessness: background report, January 23 (Reports 015250), 1995 (Box 768, Reel R-9306)
  Homeless persons -- Housing -- New York (State) -- Finance; Homeless persons -- Services for -- New York (State); Homeless persons -- Services for -- Finance -- New York (State); Housing -- Finance -- New York (State); Homelessness -- New York (State)
- Toward a national Indian legislative agenda for the 1990's: a report on national and regional tribal leaders forums (Reports 015251), 1992 (Box 768, Reel R-9306)
  Rural Poverty and Resources;Rights and Social Justice
  08500898
  American Indian Lawyer Training Program
  Indians of North America -- Government relations; Indians of North America -- Legal status, laws, etc.
- Guide for immigration advocates (Reports 015252), 1996 (Box 768, Reel R-9306, Box 769)
  08903017
  Immigrant Legal Resource Center
  1 v. (various pagings), ill., forms -- 28 cm
  Emigration and immigration law -- United States
- Public attitudes toward domestic violence: poll report: draft (Reports 015253), 1992 (Box 769, Reel R-9306)
- Meeting basic learning needs: a new vision for the 1990s: background document for World Conference on Education for All: meeting basic learning needs, Jomtien, Thailand 5-9 (Reports 015254) (Box 769, Reel R-9306)
  World Conference on Education for All: meeting basic learning needs (1990: Jomtien, Thailand)
  Education -- Congresses; Basic education; Educational equalization; Education and state
- Tribal water management handbook: "Building homelands on 19th century promises": 1985 summer course manual, June 17-28, 1985, Warm Springs Indian Reservation, Warm Springs, Oregon (Reports 015255) (Box 769, Reel R-9306)
  Rights and Social Justice;Rural Poverty and Resources
  Indians of North America -- Water rights; Water resources development; Water quality management; Irrigation
- September 1994 issue of "Reproductive rights update: ACLU quarterly reports of policy and analysis" (Reports 015256) (Box 769, Reel R-9306)
  09400758
  American Civil Liberties Union Foundation (ACLU)
  Reproductive rights update
  Human reproduction -- Law and legislation -- United States -- Periodicals; Sex instruction -- United States -- Periodicals; Sex -- Education -- United States -- Periodicals; AIDS (Disease) -- Education -- United States -- Periodicals; HIV (Viruses)
- Women's international human rights law (Reports 015257), 1994 (Box 770, Reel R-9306)
  Rights and Social Justice;DP
  09100986
  University of Toronto
  Pennsylvania studies in human rights
  Women -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Women's rights; Human rights; Feminism
- A guide for immigration advocates: Trainer's manual (Reports 015258), 1996 (Box 770, Reel R-9306)
  [Trainer's manual for "A guide for immigration advocates"]
  Emigration and immigration law -- United States; Emigration and immigration law -- United States -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.
- December 1994 issue of "Reproductive rights update: ACLU quarterly reports of policy and analysis" (Reports 015259) (Box 770, Reel R-9306)
  Abortion -- Law and legislation -- United States -- Periodicals; Abortion -- Finance -- Law and legislation -- United States -- Periodicals; Pro-choice movement -- United States -- Periodicals; Abortion -- Government policy -- Citizen participation
- Working to make a difference: law student organizing manual 1993? (Reports 015260), 1992 (Box 770, Reel R-9306)
  08900505
  National Association for Public Interest Law
  Public interest law -- United States; Law students -- United States; Student volunteers in social service -- United States -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Fund raising -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.
- Talking is the first step: governing in a racially and ethnically diverse community (Reports 015261), 1997 (Box 770, Reel R-9306)
  United States -- Race relations -- Government policy; United States -- Ethnic relations -- Government policy
- Pro bono in law schools (Reports 015262), 1991 (Box 770, Reel R-9306)
  Public interest law -- United States; Legal assistance to the poor -- United States; Law schools -- Curricula -- United States
- Jobless, penniless, often homeless: State general assistance cuts leave "employables" struggling for survival: Executive summary (Reports 015263), 1994 (Box 770, Reel R-9306)
  State general assistance cuts leave "employables" struggling for survival
  Public welfare -- United States -- States; Poor -- Employment -- United States; Homelessness -- United States
- The public service challenge: a project of the National Association for Public Interest Law (NAPIL) (Reports 015264), 1992 (Box 770, Reel R-9306)
  Public interest law -- Education, Higher -- United States; Public interest law -- Finance -- United States; Legal assistance to the poor -- Education (Higher) -- United States; Law schools -- Curricula -- United States
- Campaigning for a law school pro bono requirement (Reports 015265), 1991 (Box 770, Reel R-9306)
  Law -- Study and teaching -- United States; Public interest law -- United States; Law schools -- Curricula -- United States; Legal assistance to the poor -- United States
- Agenda: New England NAPIL regional training (Reports 015266), 1989 (Box 770, Reel R-9306)
  New England NAPIL regional training ([1989]: s.l.)
  Law -- Study and teaching -- United States -- Congresses; Public interest law -- United States -- Congresses; Law schools -- Curricula -- United States -- Congresses; Legal assistance to the poor -- United States -- Congresses
- National Housing Law Project: laying the foundation for housing justice (Reports 015267), 1993 (Box 770, Reel R-9306)
  Rights and Social Justice; Urban Poverty program
  08200966
  National Housing and Community Development Law Project
  Low-income housing -- United States; Public welfare -- United States; Legal assistance to the poor -- United States; Housing policy -- United States; Housing -- Law and legislation
- Everything you wanted to know and more about state AFDC benefits in 1992: supplement to "Living at the bottom..." (Reports 015268), 1993 (Box 771, Reel R-9306)
  Living at the bottom: an analysis of AFDC benefit levels
  Public welfare -- United States -- Statistics; Child welfare -- United States -- Statistics
- AFDC verification packet: a guide to identifying and ameliorating unnecessary verification requirements (Reports 015269), 1990 (Box 771, Reel R-9306)
  Aid to families with dependent children programs -- United States; Public welfare -- United States; Children -- Legal status, laws, etc.
- Brief amicus curiae of the National Welfare Rights and Reform Union in support of the respondents: in the Supreme Court of the United States: Eloise Anderson vs. Deshawn Green, Debby Venturella, and Diana P. Bertollt, no. 94-197 (Reports 015270), 1994 (Box 771, Reel R-9306)
  In the Supreme Court of the United States: Eloise Anderson vs. Deshawn Green: Brief amicus curiae of the National Welfare Rights and Reform Union in support of the respondents
  Aid to families with dependent children programs -- United States
- Women and the construction of human rights: 200 years of Olympe de Gouge's death (Reports 015271), 1993 (Box 771, Reel R-9306)
  United Nations World Conference on Human Rights (2nd: 1993: Vienna, Austria)
  Women's rights; Human rights
- Using a plastic card to access public benefits: the advocates' guide to electronic benefit transfer systems (EBT) (Reports 015272), 1995 (Box 771, Reel R-9306)
  Advocates' guide to electronic benefit transfer systems (EBT)
  Electronic benefits transfers -- United States; Public welfare -- United States -- Data processing
- Latino Urban Policy Agenda Project: the Latino Urban Policy Consortium draft (Reports 015273), 1996 (Box 771, Reel R-9306)
  09400361
  Latino Institute
  Hispanic Americans -- Economic conditions; Urban policy -- United States; Hispanic Americans -- Social conditions
- CD-ROM for African research needs: some basic guidelines (Reports 015274), 1993 (Box 771, Reel R-9306)
  Africa and the Middle East; Africa and the Middle East/Eastern & Southern Africa
  09400320
  American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS)
  Database searching -- Africa; CD-ROMs; CD-ROMs -- Africa
- Forum '89: National Forum for Black Public Administrators (Reports 015275), 1989 (Box 771, Reel R-9306)
  Conference materials from the 1989 conference.
  National Forum for Black Public Administrators (1989: s.l.)
- Community health studies in Kansas (Reports 015276), 1960 (Box 771, Reel R-9306)
  "Reprinted from 'American Journal of Public Health', vol. 50, no. 10, October, 1960. Copyright by the American Public Health Association, Inc." (p.1)
  American Journal of Public Health
  Public health -- Research -- Kansas
- Local initiatives in watershed management: experiences from Quirino Province, issue no. 5 of Research Brief (Reports 015277), 2000 (Box 771, Reel R-9306)
  09701951
  De La Salle University
  CEPSD research brief
  Watersheds -- Philippines; Watershed management -- Philippines; Watershed restoration -- Law and legislation -- Philippines
- Women and AIDS: developing a new health strategy: ICRW policy series (Reports 015278), 1993 (Box 771, Reel R-9306)
  09400816
  International Center for Research on Women (ICRW)
  ICRW policy series
  AIDS (Disease); AIDS (Disease) -- Prevention; Women -- Diseases
- National Domestic Violence Workplace Education Day: organizer's kit, October 1 (Reports 015279), 1996 (Box 771, Reel R-9306)
  Collection of 16 sample items for education on domestic violence for "Domestic Violence Workplace Education Day", October 1, 1996.
  Family violence; Victims of Family violence; Abused women
- Strengthening human resources: lessons learned from the Prevention of Maternal Mortality Network, 1994 draft (Reports 015280) (Box 771, Reel R-9306)
  09300229
  Maternal health care teams -- Africa -- Evaluation; Maternal health care teams -- United States; Mothers -- Mortality -- Africa; Maternal health services -- Africa -- Evaluation; Mothers -- Africa -- Mortality -- Prevention; Developing countries
- Marketing CD-ROM services: a manual for African research librarians: based on a workshop at the University of Ghana (Reports 015281), 1993 (Box 771, Reel R-9306)
  Research libraries -- Africa -- Reference services (Libraries) -- Marketing; Information storage and retrieval systems; CD-ROMs -- Africa
- Community Development Collaborative and Partnership conference: briefing book, June 19-22, 1996 (Reports 015282) (Box 771, Reel R-9306)
  09600508
  North Carolina Community Development Initiative, Inc.
  Community Development Collaborative and Partnership conference (1996: Raleigh, North Carolina)
  Community development -- Congresses; Community development corporations -- Congresses; Community development -- Endowments -- Congresses
- Second National Conference on Assisted Housing Mobility: Preliminary draft conference report (Reports 015283), 1997 (Box 771, Reel R-9306)
  Preliminary draft report in preparation for the 1998 "Second National Conference on Assisted Housing Mobility: Realizing the Promise."
  Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS)/Education
  09750784
  Business & Professional People for the Public Interest
  Housing mobility: ǂb realizing the promise: report from the Second National Conference on Assisted Housing Mobility
  National Conference on Assisted Housing Mobility (2nd: 1997: Washington, D.C.)
  Residential mobility -- United States -- Congresses; Housing policy -- United States -- Congresses; Discrimination in housing -- United States -- Congresses; Minorities -- Housing -- United States -- Congresses; Community development, Urban -- United States
- Philadelphia campaign to promote intergroup cooperation: research report (Reports 015284), 1996 (Box 771, Reel R-9306)
  "Philadelphia like other major urban centers suffers from high levels of racial and ethnic tension in its neighborhoods. This tension inhibits racial and ethnic residential integration, prevents residents from cooperating to solve neighborhood problems, a
  Race relations -- Pennsylvania (Pa.) -- Philadelphia (Pa.); Race relations -- Pennsylvania (Pa.) -- Philadelphia (Pa.) -- Statistics; Emigration and immigration -- Race relations -- Statistics; City and town life -- Race relations; Cities and towns -- Research; Ethnic conflict; Ethnic neighborhoods
- Educational activities of the Helenski Foundation of Human Rights, Warsaw: materials for the seminar on Human Rights Education, Warsaw: parts I and II, September 8-10 (Reports 015285), 1995 (Box 772, Reel R-9306)
  09550774
  Helsinki Foundation for Human Rights
  Seminar on human rights education
  Human Rights Education (1995: Warsaw, Poland)
  Human rights -- Education -- Congresses; Professional education -- Congresses; Human rights workers -- Congresses
- The Worldwide Fund for Area Studies: a report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 015286), 2002 (Box 772, Reel R-9307)
  Review of the Worldwide Fund for Area Studies
  Area studies; Endowments -- Finance
- Manual on human rights reporting: under six major international human rights instruments, Office of the High Commissioner for Human Rights, United Nations Institute for Training and Research (UNITAR), United Nations Staff College Project (Reports 015287), 1997 (Box 772, Reel R-9307)
  09600966
  International Training Centre of the ILO
  Human rights
- Report on the fourth annual Democracy and Diversity Summer Graduate Institute, Cracow Krakow, Poland, July 12 - August 2 (Reports 015288), 1995 (Box 772, Reel R-9307)
  Program description and report of the New School for Social Research, Graduate Faculty of Political and Social Science program, Democracy and Diversity Summer Graduate Institute in Krakow, Poland.
  International Affairs; Education and Culture;Rights and Social Justice
  08801174
  New School for Social Research
  Education, Higher -- International cooperation; Political science -- Education, Higher
- Conference papers from Approaches to Arms Control in Europe held in Ingles, Austria, March 23-25 (Reports 015289), 1984 (Box 772, Reel R-9307)
  08400100
  Institute for Eastwest Studies, Inc.
  Approaches to Arms Control in Europe: Ingles, Austria, March 23-25, 1984: conference papers
  Approaches to Arms Control in Europe (1984: Ingles, Austria)
  Arms control; Disarmament; Confidence and security building measures (International relations) -- Europe; Nuclear arms control -- Europe
- Torture, volume #28, no. 2 of "World medical journal" (Reports 015290), 1981 (Box 772, Reel R-9307)
  Developing Countries Program;International Affairs;Rights and Social Justice
  08400811
  World medical journal
  Torture -- Medical care; Medical ethics; Delivery of Health Care; Discrimination in medical care; Medical care -- Political aspects; Societies, Medical -- International cooperation
- Securing sovereignty: Ukraine's first five years of independence (Reports 015291), 1997 (Box 772, Reel R-9307)
  80 p. -- 28 cm.
  Sovereignty -- Ukraine; Democracy -- Ukraine
- Human rights and the medical profession in Uruguay since 1972 (Reports 015292), 1982 (Box 772, Reel R-9307)
  International Affairs;Developing Countries Program;Rights and Social Justice
  Civil rights -- Uruguay; Political prisoners -- Uruguay -- Case studies; Torture -- Uruguay -- Case studies; Physicians -- Uruguay -- Political activity; Physicians -- Civil rights -- Uruguay
- Scientists and human rights in Argentina since 1976 (Reports 015293), 1981 (Box 772, Reel R-9307)
  Human rights -- Argentina; Scientists -- Argentina -- Political activity; Scientists -- Civil rights -- Argentina; Political persecution -- Argentina
- Report of a fact-finding mission to the Philippines, November 28 - December 17 (Reports 015294), 1983 (Box 772, Reel R-9307)
  Rights and Social Justice;Developing Countries Program;International Affairs
  Report of a fact finding mission to the Philippines
  Civil rights -- Philippines; Human rights -- Philippines
- Report of a medical fact-finding mission to El Salvador, January 11-15 (Reports 015295), 1983 (Box 772, Reel R-9307)
  Medical fact-finding mission to El Salvador
  Missions, Medical -- El Salvador; Medical care -- El Salvador; Medical personnel -- Civil rights -- El Salvador; Civil rights -- El Salvador; Salvadorans -- Medical care
- The search for Brazil's disappeared: the mass grave at Dom Bosco Cemetery, March 13 (Reports 015296), 1991 (Box 772, Reel R-9307)
  Disappeared persons -- Brazil; Human rights -- Brazil; Torture -- Brazil; Political persecution -- Brazil; Political prisoners -- Brazil; Murder -- Brazil; Burial -- Brazil -- Sao Paulo (Brazil); Cemeteries -- Brazil -- Sao Paulo (Brazil); Autopsy -- Brazil; Mass burials -- Brazil
- Kenya: medicolegal aspects of the inquest into the death of Peter Njenga Karanja (Reports 015297), 1998 (Box 772, Reel R-9307)
  Civil rights -- Kenya; Physicians -- Political activity -- Kenya; Medical laws and legislation -- Kenya; Medical jurisprudence; Homicide; Human rights -- Kenya
- Guatemala: case reports, 1980-1985 and Guatemala: casos reportados 1980-1985 (Reports 015298) (Box 772, Reel R-9307)
  Case reports
  Civil rights -- Guatemala -- Periodicals; Scientists -- Guatemala -- Periodicals
- The evolution of the meaning of sexual intercourse in the human (Reports 015299), 1996 (Box 772, Reel R-9307)
  09551153
  World Health Organization (WHO)
  Leonardo series 10
  Sexual intercourse -- Congresses; Sex -- Congresses; Sex -- Religious aspects -- Congresses
- Human rights monitoring techniques: international seminar, Warsaw, Poland, December 11-13, 1995: documents (Reports 015300) (Box 772, Reel R-9307)
  Collection of seven documents from the "Human Rights Monitoring Techniques" international seminar held in Warsaw, Poland, December 11-13, 1995. Russian translation is available for both the handbook and agenda of the seminar.
  Human rights monitoring
  Human rights monitoring techniques (1995: Warsaw, Poland)